CONTACT

- (916) 817 9230
- ☑ joshharrison626@gmail.com
- Caldwell, ID, 83607
- http://www.linkedin.com/i n/jjharrison
- https://joshharrison626.git hub.io/portfolio/

SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, SCSS
- Responsive Web Design
- Wireframing and Prototyping
- Web Accessibility Standards
- Assistive Technology
- JavaScript (Native, Libraries, and Frameworks)
- UI Frameworks (React)
- Reusable UI Components (Material-UI, Custom)
- Figma (Dev Mode)
- Documentation, Presentation, and Teaching
- Creativity and Innovation

AWARDS

Accessibility Champion - Subject Matter Expert (Intuit)
This award recognizes Intuit's Accessibility leaders. They lead accessibility efforts for products and locations. They help guide product design and development for the future of Intuit.

JOSH HARRISON

UI / UX DEVELOPER

PROFILE

UI/UX Developer with 9 years of experience creating streamlined and intuitive controls and user experiences by bridging the gap between programming and design. Talented at architecting and creating high-fidelity prototypes based off of lo- and hi-fidelity designs. Consistently employs understanding of web accessibility requirements and best practices.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Intuit, Boise, ID
Frontend Staff Software Engineer

August 2022 - Present

- Co-led a team of 4 junior web developers to deliver a seamless integrated experience with QuickBooks Online and QuickBooks Time using iframe APIs, React, JavaScript, and QuickBooks theming
- Created initial proof-of-concept and framework for the time tracking integration resulting in product delivery in 6 months vs 5 years using iframe APIs, React, and JQuery
- Built the first reusable plugin using React, HTML, and CSS for the time tracking integration to support theme-switching and design tokens that could be used across all Intuit products
- Worked across teams and three internal design systems to drive web and accessibility standards and adopt design system components and tokens
- Created prototypes using React, HTML, and CSS based off of customer interviews and lo-fi designs to support design/UX concepts, prove technical feasibility, or suggest alternatives

Intuit, Boise, ID August 2021 - August 2022
Time Tracking Accessibility Leader, Staff Software Engineer

- Built a culture for accessibility that consisted of ~120 volunteer champions across development, customer support, product management, design, and research
- Created and taught an accessibility awareness class to introduce the organization to customers with disabilities, assistive technologies, and role-specific guides
- Led customer interviews to learn how features were used with assistive technologies and report bugs
- Delivered Intuits 2nd VPAT by working with an external contractor to provide an accessibility audit and lead volunteers to remediate 15 features using Microsoft Accessibility Insights and axe DevTools
- · Cont'd on next page

VOLUNTEER WORK

https://chairthehope.org/ Active volunteer: international wheelchair distributions; participate in local projects, fundraising, and create corporate partnership opportunities

ARTICLES

- Accessibility features in QuickBooks Time
- <u>Lessons Learned from an Intuit</u>
 <u>Accessibility Champion</u> Intuit
 Blog
- <u>Proving accessibility is worth it</u>
 <u>with analytics</u> Intuit Blog

WORK EXPERIENCE (CONT'D)

- Built a visually-hidden accessibility toolbar and custom keyboard shortcuts using React, HTML, and CSS and published an accessibility help guide to support customers using keyboards and screen readers
- Created a method of tracking keyboard analytics to prove accessibility usage, bug fixes, and feature discoverability; Published a blog describing the method and presented at Knowbility's AccessU 2021

Intuit, Boise, ID

February 2019 - August 2021

Sr. Software Engineer

- Led a small team of web and mobile engineers to deliver features based on location services
- Created and supported reusable web components to support location services and features
- Co-published a patent for determining location based on nearby devices (IPR-2011747US)

Intel, Hillsboro, OR

January 2015 - Januarry 2019

Web Developer

- Created training materials and led in-person training for TDD, Intro to CI/CD, and other Agile/DevOps topics
- Built and supported reusable and branded web components for all Intel IT developers
- Supported web applications built on multiple JavaScript frameworks (React, Angular, JS, etc.)
- Built proof-of-concept applications to prove and drive framework adoption (React vs Vue)

EDUCATION

B.S. in Network and Communication Management

DeVry University

GPA: 4.0

A.S. in Electrical and Computer Technology

DeVry University

GPA: 4.0